Okay, so...
Just first of all, I just wanted to sort of introduce
myself for those who don't know me. So I'm Ewan Riley.
and I am numerous.
but I'm the co-founder of Jules Co.
I'm also a manufacturing jeweler.
of 22 years and I've had my own business for
for 13 years.
So this demonstration itself will run for about 30 minutes.
minutes. I'm understanding that the south origin is on to
tonight so aware of those times for the Queen's
as a NSW in the house tonight.
So, and just to keep things flowing through.
this demonstration if you can just leave all the Q and I's
to the end. That would be great.
So yeah, I'll be taking you through the bench.
Benchflow, workflow from creating a quote through
to generating a proposal.
the client's acceptance, invoicing,
in the non-production management.
And also--
I'll show you some supply integrations that we've got.
at the moment, the pricing database.
and if you have the features we've been building from the
feedback of some of our beta testers.
So we've got 20 amazing value too.
is helping us out in this initial phase.
Yeah, so I mean, I'm in bench.
flow initially started as the e-mail.
internal project for my business and
like many of you, I was frustrated with how many different
systems we're using. I think at one point we're using seven different
systems just to make the day-to-day operations of our
custom workshop operate.
And that included spreadsheets.
and numerous other subscriptions.
I kind of got Jack of that and wanted to have
it will under one house and you know it's something
that I'd sort of started working on over a couple of years.
and especially over the last two years.
months got a lot more serious with it and the more I sort of be
to doubt the more I thought it would be very worth it.
wall for La Rada Jules to have access to it as well.
because we were finding it really helpful for our
business and to manage everything.
Yeah, that's why we've sort of been pushing really...
really hard to get this project operational.
where lots of different jillers can come on.
board and use software and hopefully
then will be a benefit to their business.
So...
So yeah, I mean let's...
Let's just keep things off.
So if you can see my screen now.
Actually, sorry, I will just mention that my camera...
members. Not very clear at all with with
my face because my main computer...
Jeter, the motherboard died this morning.
I couldn't believe it, like, you know.
all the timing. So I'm using my 10 year old diamond.
So that's why everything is super grainy.
But anyway, we'll push her and hopefully my...
My old dinosaur computer will make it through.
the end so things crossed.
So this is the main dashboard screen.
So when you get a new account, you will see
a dashboard which will have
step-by-step onboarding process.
and it will step you by.
each particular aspect.
to do in order and it will also have a
link where you can click and it will take you directly to
that different aspect that you should do before.
before you even start creating your first quote.
So what that would usually look like is
in the pricing database.
This is currently connected to Morrison Watson.
So we are working with some
companies like Ken Gold and Pat.
highloys to get them integrated into.
into the database.
This will automatically pull the pricing.
from the Morrison Watson API and
automatically uploaded every day.
As you can see here, the last sink was half an hour ago.
So, I mean, this has been a bit of a bone and continue.
for me over the years is trying to manually update all the prices.
when I'm doing quotes.
manually updating the process when I was doing quotes.
as this automatically pulls it from the system itself.
So yeah, this has been really really helpful.
you can also add in some mam.
price and if you wanted to. So this
one currently does pricing for all the castings.
and processing for the fabricated metals.
And, you know, things like 10 cards you can add in.
manual prices if you want to. In here you can also
also set your generic, you can set your markups.
And you can also put in your
scrap price that you offer for.
Clonset come in and you want to offer them, you know, up
for their scrap metal, you can add that in there too.
I just haven't got that set up quite yet.
And this is where you can also enter in all your pricing.
for your dominance.
Eli stones, currently.
just in this particular account.
So you've got rounds, but then you can also add in, you know, principle.
this cut so you can add in whatever shape you want.
So you can either put it in as a
costs per carat or a cost per sign.
And again, you can also add your markups.
in here. Again, all these markups, this is not
indication of any pricing.
This is just generic information for us to work with.
with is also a section for lab growth.
So you can split out your nose.
natural and your lab grounds, you can add in all your
gemstones in here and etc etc you can
add in the cost for settings.
as in, sorry, like how much it costs to
to set a stone and then you can put your mark
up in there as well. Same with chains if you've got some.
any particular chains which
you want to integrate into the system.
you can put the price per gram.
in here and then again your generic markups.
It has a spot for findings.
Michelais.
So the library section, this is where you're adding all your library.
for your various different components.
So now, you know, if you have
slightly different fee for manufacturing versus
There's card design.
You can input them in there.
So--
It's really important that this pricing database is filled out.
from the start because then this
This is what the quote pulls all the...
information from. So it allows you to do a quiet end.
in 30 seconds if all this is filled out correctly.
And in this business section you can just turn it on.
how much deposit you wanted to.
How much deposit you want to take for each person.
particular job and then you can also add in custom categories.
But yeah, this is just one very important part.
to get that all filled out correctly.
And I mean, but yeah, the more.
I mean once this is set up then you don't
really have to tinker with it too much especially.
with having this metal integration.
Thanks for more.
and Watson. I mean they came gold one.
is going to be coming next.
But yeah, for now we just have Morrison Watson there been
really fast and really good to deal with.
So I'll just quickly go.
So this is actually--
in beta mode at the moment so you'll see a lot of
things we've been updating all about.
users with the different updates. So this won't be
here. So this just shows that there's
It's been connected to Morrison Watson's confirmation.
of that. This talks about different quites.
that are in the system, how many clients you have.
that are imported and all the different parts.
puzzles you've sent. So again this is just all test information.
for now.
So this is the client data.
So again, this is where you can do it.
bulk import of all your existing clients from your existing city.
CRM. So that's it.
That's another thing which is good to do from the get go.
as well is inputting all your clients.
So there is, when this initial...
initial screen comes up it will have a certain
fields that it will require so you know it will need it.
your name, email and a phone number from the clients.
if you're doing a bulk import.
And it also will allow any birthday.
are anniversaries to be imported as well but if you want to make
manually add a client in, you can do that here.
I want to do it on this screen or do it in the quotes.
screen. But yeah, you can definitely.
manually add your clients in here.
So this is where the magic happens.
in this particular screen.
So if we go to...
a new full quote.
This is where we can begin the process of
starting the quote.
So with this quoting system, you can
can add in multiple options. So we will do just
the two option quote just so you can see
what it is. So in this option title,
option title section you'd want to put
what that particular option is.
So for example,
If you were quoting on an engaging the system
was a solitary gadget ring.
So in here,
you might put adding her like old.
engagement ring, the completion.
and time frame so this is more so important when it comes through.
to drafting up the proposal. So let's see.
say you know four to six weeks.
option description. So this
This is where you put a more detailed.
a more detailed description of what it actually
is as opposed to just the title. So let's just put adding
our yellow garden gauge ring with one.
carrot, mines, diamonds.
This is capable of simple just for this.
particular sample.
In here you can add in a piece.
feature.
So let's just put it in.
this one. So you can
add up to six pitches so this will be where you put your
designs for any particular client.
Okay, and in here's a...
This is where we're creating a new client or adding.
or searching for an existing client.
So let's just
It's probably random name.
Billy Bob.
But I'm it is my Billy Bob quants currently in this is
system. So we'll create a new client.
You have to add in
an email address.
And a final number.
So that will then create a new client.
So it's already found...
It has found an existing
that you enroll in the database.
That's not correct.
Let's try that again.
Let's just put in a random email.
and a random phone number.
Okay, so that is created in new client.
which will then be automatically updated and put in
into the quantity.
database.
So, a quite name. So, this is...
This is where we will just put gadget ring.
This is where you just keep it very generic.
So this is, you can allocate a bit too much.
process to this. So, you know, if for example,
example if you are doing a cast chunk.
in a handmade setting, for example.
We would put it as a custom hybrid CAD.
So hybrid, we refer that to you as, you know,
something which is utilizing both CAD and
handmade techniques. So we'll put that on the
job type. So this is just helpful when it comes down to
reporting later on. You can split out your
different proportions with
you know, the different type of processes you would create.
a piece of jurien.
Again, categories same sort of thing, it will help for reporting later.
on so you want to fill this out and this is just the current date.
In here you can add some internal notes.
Sometimes you get clients in or a bit of a...
or you know it can be extra special.
So, you know, this is where you can put any internal nights in.
So say, "Hey."
Very, funny.
So the client won't see this. This is just be sure.
shown for internal purposes. In here you can start importing
or the client measurements.
So for example, being the gauge.
measuring the Cise size M about if it's a necklace.
or brice that you can put in the measurements in here.
And if they're buying it for a gift for some...
You can add this in here. You can say it's gift for
Mary.
and it's for an engagement and the date.
But they're getting engaged, is going to be...
the 30th of August.
We want to make sure that we're going to get it done at least, you know, good co-
couple weeks beforehand.
put in for the 16th. So this is all useful when it comes to
to sending the proposal. In here you can add in
any extra personal notes or any
extra information you might want to add.
Okay, so this is where we're the
The magic starts to happen here, so when we start putting in the labour out,
It will come across into the quite summary and will lock
and we'll update this live as you go.
So let's say for
For example, we want to spend an hour doing the CAD.
and then to actually assemble the cap to
actually a symbol or the labor hours working on
on the casting itself.
So, you know,
we might spend two hours cleaning up that and then
And if we want to add in some hand-for-handmade.
cause or some handmade components in it.
we can section that off so we might want to add
maybe six hours for that.
can see here as we start typing this in.
the pricing will start to update. So this is
information is being pulled from that
pricing database so that's where it's important to make sure that's filled out.
and being a character.
cast autumn. There's a B printing fee.
So again, this is all put into the back end.
pricing database. So there's
Let's say there's one component.
and then there's one casting on them.
So this will be updated.
on the quite summary here.
So this is an additional labour item.
So this has been a request from some of the beta users.
So you
You know, they've been wanting to add in specific.
Labor items which
that just gives them an option to add in
some extra fees. So for example,
if...
I don't know if I needed to.
add in, do some more card, card work.
for a different component they need to be used.
initially planned on, they can add that in there.
But this this needs a little bit of reform it, but yeah, it will
as a request so we'll work on refining that a little bit.
bit more because it will probably make it more of a
of a custom kind of labour situation as opposed to...
to maybe adding in these extra.
sections here. Yep, then we come to
setting so again these are all pre-filled in the
back end. Not so pre-filled that these are
in the pricing database so you can
you can change these but you know a new account will
or just automatically list all these setting options.
So in this particular case, we want to do a core setting of three.
It's a round stein.
It's one stone. The cost, you know, it will
automatically pull this cost in from the pricing database, but what's the
So, you know, it's gonna be a tricky style,
so we might wanna...
charge it out at cost $100.
This is a--
put your mark up in and again we'll show you
Precious Metal, again this is...
is pulling directly from the Mars and Watson feed.
So, casting metal.
Thank you.
I got all three grams.
Actually, let's change that to 4.
Let's say there's a bit of adding care.
What goals?
Let's just do that.
example. So this is where we got our pricing updated here.
adding in a center star.
So currently I don't have any sense of diamonds.
add-ins to pricing database. So this is
where we'll do say one carrot, you put in your color.
- Marty.
You can add in certificate. This is a...
the cost is five grand.
the two mark up and that's reflected in the quote over here.
you know if there's any change.
You can add in change findings.
miscellaneous, so that's where you can add in valuations.
or kind of charge for packaging, shipping, insurance, what.
kind of stuff you can add that in there and if there's any scraps.
You can also add that in.
which will then...
Okay, so what am I?
head back just into the...
original quite we did and just do a second option here.
Just so I can show you what's accepting a...
multi-stage proposal looks like.
So, what we can actually do...
is we can actually duplicate.
create this particular option.
So, as you're having to input all the details again.
especially if you're just quoting like
adding character versus nine characters.
so we can just hit that.
It will create.
I see.
the emerald version of it.
can change through the details here saying we're doing 9 characters.
We will look what else we need to change.
We will change.
the mouse in the middle.
And we would change.
the black gold.
As you can see here, it's reflected that in the
So this is the original price here 18,300.
363 and in 9 carat 16,000.
540. Just make sure you're thinking about it.
is so good, which is...
Okay, so that is
Another feature of this is that it automatically saves.
throughout the process as well.
So if you
If you do go out of the screen, it will be a great way to do it.
be saved as you go.
and be safe just like a draft.
We'll hit update.
Okay, and what we'll do now is we'll create a new video.
the proposal so you just one click of a button.
button and it creates a new proposal.
So this is the--
client facing side.
This is where you'd fill in the details that will be.
sense of the client for them to approve the quote.
The quote.
Function is purely for in-house purposes.
So this introduction message
closing message here that's all pre-filled in the sitting section.
beforehand so this will automatically pull in what you've
written and it also will have
and all the quite is valid for, so this again can be changed.
So this is
This is going to order populate.
some of the options in the pricing etc.
from the quite crowd so you just need to email.
put it from the quote. So this is the
quite redid up.
And as you can see, it's pulled in...
that information and because we had two options.
you've got your 18 karat yellow gold here and your 9 karat yellow gold.
here and it's put in the pricing.
We'll just head back up here for a sec because
You got a payment schedule here, so some people like to take
it's a new percent deposit something would like to take a few
center puzzle so you can actually add this in here.
It does have some pre-filled.
ones down below. So let's just say in this particular case,
take a few percent deposit with the balance.
paid at different times.
This one, this is after accepting the proposal.
then, you know,
they need to have 24 hours to pay.
got the price breaking down and then the final balance.
Once we can set it to the end.
as percentage or fixed.
I've got in this particular case it's just a remaining balance.
because we're doing a 50% deposit and a 50% deposit.
to be sent before they collect.
You can also choose some different options here.
whether you want them to pay before.
we stop production, we can click that option.
So, let's see.
this sections part is
when, for example, if you were quite...
on the Engage Ring and they also want to
it a bracelet you would sectional
off the engagement ring as one.
as one section and then the
Brice it will be sectioned off as a separate section.
So we do--
that because we've got multiple options for the gauge rings.
so they can still pick either 18 carat or 9 carat.
and then also they can then choose to accept the
bracelet as well. This particular case because there's
only one item technically required, which is
engagement we might need to section it off.
So we just want to double check these off.
field correctly.
If you do want to display the...
price of the stone individually in the proposal you can.
can just toggle this on when most people don't.
usually do that but you can decide to do that if you wish.
[chuckles]
This is where you would upload that is
So on again, we will actually get this pulling in from the corner.
but for now it's just a manual upload of the
Design again.
Boop.
So you can attach up to six images again.
Let's just leave this one off for now.
You can also choose to, you know,
So give them a little discount if you wish or like.
complimentary add on like complimentary.
polishing cloth etc. EK
and set up a template for this mistake.
I'll just leave it off.
So once that's all done, you just need to click Save.
and then you can send it directly to the client.
So you can also copy the link if you want to text
to them or send a via WhatsApp etc but in the
to the case, we will send it for email.
is just a random generic email.
and or generic but it's just a random email and
And this can be filled out as a template.
and you can put whatever you wish on here but it has the link.
Thank you for the centre of the coin.
the link that I'll click on. So we'll do those clicks send.
That will send it.
directly to the client.
But what we might actually do...
is actually Senator Real.
e-mail address.
So I can show you what it looks like from the client side.
Okay, so.
I will pop back into the...
email address and I'll show you what that looks like.
Okay, so this is what the decline is.
we'll see. It will come through.
In the email, I have some branding.
This city could be--
link.
So this is really options will come up so the design will come up.
you can choose to watermark it.
particularly your design. You'll have the title of the
and this is the description.
So that can be filled out in that quote screen.
It will just sort of break down.
materials that are in the
piece. So they've got their two options.
So let's say for example, I want to go ahead and say, "I'm going to go ahead and do this."
I have with the adding card option or they need to do so.
Select it.
and then it will bring up the deposit they need.
pay, but also do the terms and conditions.
So again, this is all pre-filled on the back end.
This is just confirmation.
that they have happy with those terms and conditions.
This is just accepting the fact that you're not going to be able to get the right answer.
quote and from their end I'll say the
So clearly see that it's accepted.
and they can then keep this for their records.
So then we'll head back into the bench.
So I dashboard now.
Okay, so this is just back in the proposal section.
So as you can see here, you can see that it's been.
second in the letter I've seen it.
which has been confirmed and they have signed it.
teas and teas. So this then will then it will
automatically create two things.
One thing it will create.
is you'll head into the production.
board. So this is where the
workflow management starts to happen.
the other.
in this particular section, you can
it breaks down all the different steps.
have this so you can remove certain steps.
all the way but it's sort of pre-filled these out for now.
So it's also called in
some data from the actual question.
itself. So you
these can obviously be changed.
You can also track how many they actually take as well.
and put that into the workflow.
You can change the status.
of the job itself. So currently
it's not started but you know you can click
that has been scheduled out.
priority you can then also change
materials have been ordered not.
And if you're waiting on any particular thing like...
For example, still waiting for the gemstone to come.
etc. Change it due date.
I can obviously click where the polls being received or not.
You can add in pictures here.
This is where you can upload any sort of vent shots or renders.
the designs again.
You can apps 25 photos for this particular one.
You will also then be able to
be able to allocate team members to each other.
particular stage.
As you can see here, because we click schedule, we're scrolling into the next.
next step.
So this is where you can add in all your tools.
Again, this is just generic information.
So here's just got some pre-filled out.
particular person is a jeweler and a polisher.
So they productive for season.
sales a day and productive 24 hours a week.
This turnaround dates is more suitable for contractors.
Obviously, if you inhale, there's no turnaround days per se.
Bye.
If you want to...
add a new team member you simply add them in.
here. But they are and you just add
them into your team here.
Then you can also add in your contractors.
So, I'm just taking the case.
I'm going to end grave up.
Turn around, Tom's usually.
10 days and it takes two days in trouble.
You've also got a calendar function here once you start scheduling.
jobs out. This will be showing up within the calendar itself.
and then you can drag and drop things around as you go that will reflect.
back into the job itself.
So, family change dates.
So this is quite a big...
This is quite a big feature.
but we're still working out the nitty gritty parts here.
But within a week we should have this.
pretty running smoothly. This is going to be it.
a quite an exciting feature, especially
considering it pulls in as soon as proposal exists.
was accepted. The headshot.
in production. We will also...
be making sure that when a proposal
is accepted it would be automatically generate an invoice.
and that invoice would automatically be...
sent to the client as well. So that will be generated up here.
It will work very similarly.
a proposal not only will it all make
But you can also push it
manually to the client as well.
and you know it will have clearly everything split out.
into different payments you can generate a
If you wish, any other stuff.
messages you want to give them but this will also be...
branded pretty much identical to the proposal itself.
>> Okay.
we come to the reporting section so this for
is reasonably generic.
say it just outlines the amount of questions.
you've created obviously the proposal you sent months that
and it talks about your conversion rate, which is obviously how you can do it.
helpful for tracking. So you know you can
if that is a low number,
can work on increasing your conversions by maybe changing your
some wording in your proposals or doing something.
offering them something slightly extra.
as just an extra incentive for them to go ahead.
And then it just titles the amount of revenue you've collected.
it over time and the average job value.
So, and then yeah, an obviously sort of break.
stand and imagine here as well.
So you can then expo--
this data and, you know, for any
the, you know, keeping
track measuring any sort of thing you want to measure.
This will be built out over time to
become a...
some more reporting.
Yeah, the
more reports available is what I'm trying to say.
in here and we do have a plan to
integrate zero within the next month.
So any job that is invoiced out.
Any payments that are made will be integrated.
of zero. So that's pretty exciting that we're going to
get that integrated sooner rather than later.
So yeah, as time goes on this one.
be a bit more customizable and you can choose to.
have particular things in here or not.
just keep it really simple and just have one that you sort of want to track in between.
particular but yeah this will be more customizable in the future.
Um...
That is pretty much the workflow from start to finish.
So as you can see it covers from getting the...
their client into the system, all our through quotes, proposals.
invoices, production workflow.
and yeah and then
and tracking measuring.
everything throughout the stages.
So we touched on the pricing database.
a little bit. So in this setting section this is where you're into
Sorry, in New Year.
So you can change all the colors.
You can add all that in there.
This is where you add your quote.
Come on, the quotes about it.
for and you can also assign some
team members so you know if you've got
a front of house that you want to invite.
you can just add the mean here. You can allocate who they actually are.
or what sort of level of...
what sort of level that user can access.
the platform and it will send an email.
to them to add into the system.
Yeah, and this is
where you're also, this is important to set up before you keep things on.
is to all the different weddings that are
you want to have in the quads or proposals.
You can
can also protect the designs by having
the images overlaid.
with your logo or anything else.
So yeah, that also protects all the designs that
that you send through to them.
So yeah, it will take about...
you know 30 minutes to to set up your account properly.
But like I said earlier on, mindset's
done, then you won't really need to do it.
again because...
all this would be automatically polls and it's so much.
to sit and forget unless you want to update it of course.
You can adjust your...
GP guidelines in here as well.
And
This is where another place of this is.
the place where you set up your supply integrations as well.
during the onboarding it will direct you to here and
and this is where if you do use Morrison Watson.
This is where you start to set up all this.
This seems really complicated, but...
We've got some help functions available to help.
help connect with this and Marisam Watson are also able to
help as well if you call them. But they have a lot of
allowed every user of their own.
platform to access their APIs.
So yeah, again, it looks very complicated, but once it's set up...
It will import all this property.
pricing on a daily basis.
And last thing we have also in the chat.
integrated a full help system into this.
And so we have
currently about 70 articles in the back end.
So, you know, if you want to know...
How to create?
I quote...
It will pop up here in this little message bar.
and then it will show the different articles that you can then click on.
and look at to get help if you need help with any aspect.
of it during the time.
and this is where you need this is if you need to contact some
AKA me. It will.
be able to send a message to me and
I'll be able to action and help you out.
We will be offering
a, um, we're.
also will be offering onboarding as well.
15 minute onboarding call if you need any
help with actually sitting here.
everything up. And if you find a bug.
Please, please report it.
that will allow us to fix it and
A great thing about the way that we have.
produces platform is that we can fix a bug and
get it live within five minutes.
So it's not.
something that will take months and months and months to do.
is very very quick so we can move very
and same if you have an idea that
of a feature you want to add, please request.
it because the more people will request a particular feature.
is
Obviously shows us what the demand is and then we can
and again input that feature in and get it live.
the next day so we can do
off really really quickly which is which is very exciting.
So that is everything.
That is everything inside the system.
And so I'll book.
put a link in the chat.
if you want to pre-register your interest.
because you do get a discount.
If you pre-read.
register your interest in signing up to the platform.
I will actually extend that out.
for a month. I was initially
you're just gonna do it until the launch, which is tomorrow.
I will extend it out because I do realize that
There will be still some bugs that will soon end be found.
and things might not be.
running 100% smoothly so we'll extend out.
for any users that sign up.
within the month then they will get a perfect
a lifetime discount.
for the life and our access to all the premium features.
ongoing as well. So that basically
ends with demonstration and...
If you do have any questions, please.
feel free to ask or you can also
So send me an email.
So that is support at
at benchflow.app.
put that in the chat as well.
But if you do need to contact me via email, that is
the email to sender2.